osaa.org 2018-12-24

# OSAA - Privacy Policy

The OSAA recognizes that the growth of on-line services, including Internet services, has created additional privacy concerns, particularly for our constituents. On-line privacy concerns focus on the protection of "person identifiable" information, which an individual reasonably expects to be kept private. As the term suggests, "person identifiable" information is information which can be associated with a specific individual or entity, including, for example, a person's name, address or telephone number, e-mail address, and information about on-line activities that are directly linked to them. 

The OSAA knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This notice describes our privacy policy for the OSAA website. 

## Information Collection

If you browse the OSAA website, you do so anonymously. We do not collect personal information. We may log your IP address (the Internet address of your computer) to give us an idea of which parts of our website you visit, but we do not link your IP address to anything personally identifiable. This site's activity data is used only for standard reporting purposes to evaluate site content and performance. 

Some of the services on our website require user authentication and authorization. Personal information provided for OSAA website user accounts may be collected. This information is used to track user accounts and preferences as well as adding another layer of security. This information may include your name, e-mail address, phone number, job title, and/or mailing address. 

Like many other websites, we use a standard technology called a ["cookie"](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie). On confidential information pages, you may accept cookies but they are not essential for site security. These cookies are used to remember your login information and reside on your computer in encrypted format. These cookies persist throughout your browsing experience and live on through closing your browser. The cookies are discarded as soon as you log off through the website. Other cookies are used to remember your browsing preferences like which specific classification you viewed last to aide the user experience. These cookies persist across your browning sessions. 

## Disclosure

The OSAA does not sell, trade, or otherwise disclose any person identifiable information in any manner. Visitor IP addresses are not discoverable on this website nor are they disclosed to third-parties. Information provided by users and associated with a school, like names and job titles, are displayed on this website in addition to school and entity contact information which is readily available elsewhere. However, individuals' contact information is intended for the use of OSAA Staff only and is not disclosed to third-parties without permission from the individual user. 

## Security

The OSAA is fully committed to data security. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure your information. The security of your information is protected during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts transmitted information. In addition to built in SSL security protocols, more sensitive information, like user passwords, are encrypted with a custom written algorithm that cannot be decrypted. We will continue to enhance our security procedures as new technology becomes available. 

We urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal data. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your access codes and to your computer. Do not share your access codes with others. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. 

## Other Website Services

This website may contain links to other websites and the OSAA is not responsible for privacy and security practices of those websites. 

Several on-line services, like e-commerce, are utilized by the OSAA through other website or on-line service providers, like PayPal. The OSAA is not responsible for privacy and security practices of those websites. Please refer to the hosting service provider's privacy information for specific guidance on security protocols.
